

Dominic Fung

Bioinformatics and Statistics (BSc.)

Mississauga ON. Canada

Skills

Full stack development	5+ yrs.
Cloud computing/ Serverless technology	3+ yrs.
Web dev. & design	4+ yrs.
App (IOS/Android) development	2+ yrs.
Big data/ Data science	2+ yrs.
Distributed legder technology	1+ yrs.

Frameworks & Technologies

Typescript & Javascript	4+ yrs.
Reactjs & React-Native	4+ yrs.
AWS serverless	3+ yrs.
Python & Tensorflow	2+ yrs.
AWS Sagemaker	2+ yrs.
Java/ Kotlin/ Swift	1+ yrs.

Biography

Dominic is from Mississauga, Ontario where he works as a technical specialist at BMO. Dom has 5 years of experience as a software developer with a focus on full-stack Javascript & Typescript app development hosted on AWS. He's also dabbled in AI and blockchain technologies using Tensorflow and tested smart contracts on NEO respectively. In his spare time, Dom plays acoustic renditions of 2000s punkrock songs on his guitar and listens to Millennial Investing by The Investors's Podcast Network.

Work Experience

Technical Specialist | BMO

RPA, Data & AI - SmartCore

May 2017 - today

Helped deploy multiple Workfusion platform environments. Wrote multiple, reusable Java libraries on Workfusion such as DB connectors and SMTP/IMAP classes shared across projects. Built a Reactjs app to monitor the health of virtual desktop images hosted on our environments. Built a video streaming platform using videojs and RTMP to monitor robotic process automations in real-time. Created dashboards via PowerBI, reporting on server status, platform capacity and tracking in-flight automation projects.

IT Consultant | FDM Group

Jan 2017 - May 2019

Toronto, GTA

Focused on helping customers build Java applications using relational DB backends. We utilized Spring Boot and the MVC design pattern.

Projects

Oslyn.io | Your digital bandmate

Android & IOS App



Oslyn is an app that listens to you play and accompanies you in real-time with a wide selection of pads, synths, and sounds.

As a data scientist, I used Tensorflow and AWS Sagemaker to train and improve multiple model architectures (ie. Feed Forward, Recurrent Neural Net, etc.) utilizing 400+ labelled songs and pretraining on audio scraped from the internet to achieve increased accuracy.

As a developer, I used AWS Amplify to authenticate and connect to our cloud infrastructure. Amplify Cognito for authentication. DynamoDB & AWS Appsync (graphQL) to store user data, model information, etc. S3 was used for sound and model files. I used React-Native + Java & Swift deployed on the Play Store and App Store for Android and IOS respectively.

Nodis.io | Get Noticed

Webapp and Blockchain



Nodis' goal is to help small businesses around the world to get noticed by local communities. Nodis Challenge is our fun and interactive way to reach that goal. Nodis is a cryptocurrency, built on the NEO blockchain using Reactjs and MongoDB hosted on AWS EC2. I also helped test the smart contract on the NEO test network using Python.

https://github.com/nodis-io

Education

2011 - 2016

Bioinformatics (BSc.) and Minor Statistics

University of Toronto Mississauga

Interests

- Playing Music
- Snowboarding
- ▶ All things Marvel

Contact

- 1406 Pickwick Dr. Mississauga ON. L5V 1V7
- \Box +1 647 622 7764
- dominic.fung@icloud.com
- ★ http://dom-fung.com
- github.com/DominicFung

One Chanhs Co. | Bridal store

Serverless React store



Built with React and AWS Appsync. Stripe API for monetization. Used tailwind.css to allow my client greater design customizability.

https://github.com/DominicFung/onechanhs

Logistical.ly

Desktop app via React-Electron



Windows desktop app built with Typescript, React and Electron to help a client find the lowest courier cost given a list of destinations and courier services.

https://github.com/DominicFung/logistical.ly

Certifications



Amazon Web Services Solutions Architect Associate

Amazon Web Services (AWS) HDW98122JFRQQBGT



SAS Certified Advanced Programmer for SAS 9

SAS Institute AP019093v9



MTA: Database Fundamentals - Certified 2016

Microsoft 13090778

15th May 2021	
	Dom Fung